TERWILLIGER FAMILY COLLECTION (MSS141) 1912-1919
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Terwilliger Family Collection 1912-1919
nam_mss141
0.40
Beebe, Harvey
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The Terwilliger Family Collection contains numerous letters written by Harvey Beebe, an American soldier from southwestern New York during World War I.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Gordon Terwilliger, grandson of Harvey Beebe, donated this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections in 2014.
Biographical Sketch
Harvey Beebe was from Falconer, New York. He worked at the National Chautauqua County Bank until 1918, when he left his position to serve in the Navy during World War I. Beebe completed basic training in the United States and then served in France during the war. He returned home and was stationed in Hampton Roads, Virginia beginning in February 1919. During his service, Beebe frequently wrote letters home to his family, especially his mother Grace Frankenfield, and future wife, Hazel Ames. Harvey and Hazel Beebe married in early 1919 after his return to the United States and their daughter was Shirley Beebe Terwilliger.
Scope and Content Information
The vast majority of this collection is handwritten correspondence sent by Harvey Beebe to his family and girlfriend back home. There are some additional items such as correspondence from others, Beebe's local draft board card, a machine gun manual, and a list of sailors staying in a U.S. Naval Barrack in France.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized chronologically. There are no series.
Subject and Genre Headings
Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Military and Armed Conflict; Travel; Military and Armed Conflict; Harvey Beebe; World War, 1914-1918--Personal narratives, American.; World War, 1914-1918--Naval operations, American.; Correspondence
Container List
- Correspondence, 1912; 1914; 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 42nd Annual Report of Prudential Insurance Company, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Harvey Beebe Draft Car, Troop Billet Ticket, and Article about Leaving for War, 1918; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1918 January-1918 April (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1918 July (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1918 August (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1918 September (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1918 October (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1918 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1918 December (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1919 January-1919 April (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lewis Machine Gun Manual, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- List of Sailors in Barracks 12 of the U.S. Naval Station in Pauillac, France, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Notes and Math, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)